Guide to the Victor F. Germack and Lori Shepard Germack Collection of Photographs of Indians of North America
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Victor F. Germack and Lori Shepard Germack Collection of Photographs of Indians of North America.
1850-1978
1860-1925
WA Photos 483
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
12.15
(28 boxes)
This collection consists chiefly of photographic materials created circa 1850-1978 that depict American Indians, including informal and studio portraits, as well as photographs that show the natural and built environment of the American West. Images of the American West include views of cities and towns, mining and logging operations, railroads, and natural scenery.
Germack, Victor F.
Barry, D. F. (David Francis), 1854-1934
Briggs, Francis Chickering, 1833-1908
Brown, Henry (William Henry), 1844-1886
Chickering, Munroe, 1846-
Gardner, Alexander, 1821-1882
Germack, Lori
Gifford, Benjamin A., 1859-1936
Hartwell, Francis Asher
Hillers, John K., 1843-1925
Illingworth, W. H. (William H.), 1842-1893
Ingersoll, T. W. (Truman Ward), 1862-1922
Jackson, William Henry, 1843-1942
Lummis, Charles Fletcher, 1859-1928
Moorhouse, Lee, 1850-1926
Morrow, Stanley J., 1843-1921
Muhr, Adolph F., -1913
Rinehart, F. A. (Frank A.)
Whitney, Joel E. (Joel Emmons), 1822-1886
Wittick, Ben, 1845-1903
Florida Club (Cooperative)
Keystone View Company
Thomas Houseworth & Co
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Vintage Photographic on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana and Walter McClintock Memorial Fund, 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Victor F. Germack (born 1939) and Lori Shepard Germack (born 1942)
Victor F. Germack, and his wife, Lori Shepard Germack, are collectors of photographs.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists chiefly of photographic materials created circa 1850-1978 that depict American Indians, including informal and studio portraits, as well as photographs that show the natural and built environment of the American West. Images of the American West include views of cities and towns, mining and logging operations, railroads, and natural scenery.
The collection comprises a broad range of photographic formats including cased photographs, tintypes, card photographs, stereographs, transparencies, photographic postcards, and other photographic prints, as well as photograph albums and photographically illustrated books. Other visual resources in the collection include printed material, such as picture postcards, cigarette cards, playing cards, and photomechanical prints.
Prominent photographers represented in the collection include David Francis Barry, William Henry Brown, Alexander Gardner, Benjamin Arthur Gifford, Francis Asher Hartwell, John Karl Hillers, William H. Illingworth, Truman Ward Ingersoll, William Henry Jackson, Charles Fletcher Lummis, Thomas Leander Moorhouse, Stanley Julius Morrow, Adolph F. Muhr, Timothy H. O'Sullivan, Frank Albert Rinehart, Joel Emmons Whitney, and Benjamin Wittick.
Major studios, photograph cooperatives, and companies represented in the collection include Florida Club, Keystone View Company, and Thomas Houseworth & Co.
A significant group of photographs by Francis Chickering Briggs and Munroe Chickering document students, buildings, and environs of the Santee Normal Training School in Santee, Nebraska, in 1877, as well as schools at the Cheyenne River Reservation in the Dakota Territory and the Ponca Agency in Nebraska.
Each folder contains a single item, except when noted in the description.
Material in the collection are arranged by type and size, consequently images by a single photographer may appear in multiple series.
Arrangement
Organized into eight series: I. Cased Photographs, Tintypes, and Orotone, circa 1850-circa 1960. II. Card Photographs, 1863-circa 1910. III. Stereographs, circa 1860-circa 1925. IV. Photographic Prints, 1862-1927. V. Photograph Albums and Photographically Illustrated Volumes, 1875-circa 1969. VI. Photographic Transparencies, circa 1878-circa 1920. VII. Postcards, circa 1900-1978. VIII. Printed Material and Press Kit, 1899-1975.
Cities and towns -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Indians of North America -- Pictorial works; Indians of North America -- Portraits; Mineral industries -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Photographers -- West (U.S.); Playing cards -- West (U.S.); Railroads -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Tourism -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Cheyenne River Indian Reservation (S.D.) -- Pictorial works; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Women -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Card photographs (photographs); Visiting cards; Cyanotypes (photographic prints); Photograph albums; Photographic prints; Playing cards; Tintypes (prints); Stereographs; Mining engineering -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Mines and mineral resources -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Barry, D. F. (David Francis), 1854-1934; Briggs, Francis Chickering, 1833-1908; Brown, Henry (William Henry), 1844-1886; Chickering, Munroe, 1846-; Gardner, Alexander, 1821-1882; Germack, Lori; Germack, Victor F.; Gifford, Benjamin A., 1859-1936; Hartwell, Francis Asher; Hillers, John K., 1843-1925; Illingworth, W. H. (William H.), 1842-1893; Lummis, Charles Fletcher, 1859-1928; Moorhouse, Lee, 1850-1926; Morrow, Stanley J., 1843-1921; Muhr, Adolph F., -1913; Rinehart, F. A. (Frank A.); Whitney, Joel E. (Joel Emmons), 1822-1886; Wittick, Ben, 1845-1903; Florida Club (Cooperative); Keystone View Company; Santee Normal Training School (Santee, Neb.); Santee Normal Training School (Santee, Neb.) -- Pictorial works; Thomas Houseworth & Co; United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Ponca Agency -- Pictorial works
- Cased Photographs, Tintypes, and Orotone, circa 1850-circa 1960; Series I; 1.1; (1 box)
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized into four subseries: Daguerreotype, Ambrotypes, Tintypes, and Orotone.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of a daguerreotype, two ambrotypes, and fifteen tintypes by unidentified photographers, as well as an orotone by Arthur Clarence Pillsbury.
  - Daguerreotype
    - Boy and Girl, Possibly American Indians, Posed Sitting and Half Figures, the Former Holding a Dog, circa 1850 (Box 1A, Folder 1)
      Sixth-plate hand-tinted daguerreotype in a full leather case.
  - Ambrotypes
    - American Indian Man Posed Sitting, Half Figure, circa 1850 (Box 1A, Folder 2)
      Sixth-plate hand-tinted clear-glass ambrotype in a half leather case.
    - Copy Photograph of an American Indian Family; Man Posed Standing, Woman Posed Sitting, and Infant in a Cradleboard, Full Figures, circa 1890, circa 1950-1960 (Box 1A, Folder 3)
      Replica sixth-plate ambrotype in a full leather case. The "ambrotype" in this example is positive silver gelatin emulsion on glass, probably a lantern slide.
  - Tintypes
    - American Indian Woman Posed Standing, Full Figure, and Holding a Tomahawk, circa 1860 (Box 1A, Folder 4)
      Quarter-plate hand-tinted tintype in a full leather case.
    - Six American Indian Men Wearing Regalia and Holding Tomahawks, Clubs, and Pipes, as well as a European American Man, circa 1860-1865 (Box 1D, Folder 5)
      Full-plate hand-tinted tintype and brass mat.
    - American Indian Man Posed Sitting, Half Figure, circa 1880 (Box 1B, Folder 6)
      Sixth-plate tintype in an embossed paper sleeve.
    - Copy Photograph of Little Crow, Dakota Indian, Posed Sitting, Half Figure, circa 1870 (Box 1B, Folder 7)
      General note
      Original portrait by Joel Emmons Whitney, 1862
      Sixth-plate tintype in a full leather case.
    - American Indian Man and a European American Man, Posed Sitting and Full Figures, circa 1881 (Box 1B, Folder 8)
      Pencil inscription on board in image package: "M. B. V_____ and Yellow Bull / Year 1881."
      Possibly Yellow Bull (Tsutlim-moxmox), a Nez Percé Indian Man.
      Not housed in its original case; inscription in pencil under the image package: "Ed Stone's Mother."
    - American Indian Man and a European American Man, Posed Sitting and Full Figures, circa 1880 (Box 1B, Folder 9)
      Sixth-plate tintype.
    - American Indian Man with Tattooed Checks Posed Sitting, Full Figure, and Holding a Tomahawk, circa 1880 (Box 1B, Folder 10)
      Sixth-plate hand-tinted tintype.
    - American Indian Woman Posed Sitting, circa 1880 (Box 1B, Folder 11)
      Quarter-plate hand-tinted tintype.
    - American Indian Man and Woman Posed Sitting, Full Figures, circa 1880 (Box 1B, Folder 12)
      Sixth-plate hand-tinted tintype in a frame.
    - American Indian Man Posed Sitting, Half Figure, Wearing a Hat and Fringed Shirt, and Wrapped Braids, circa 1870 (Box 1B, Folder 13)
      Half-plate tintype.
    - American Indian Man, identified as Standing Bear, Posed, circa 1870 (Box 1B, Folder 14)
      The man in the image is not Standing Bear (Ma-chú-nu-zhe, Ma-chú-na-zhe or Mantcunanjin), the Ponca Indian chief.
    - Three American Indian Men, One Man Posed Standing Between Two Men Posed Sitting, Full Figures, in the Tent of a Traveling Photographer, circa 1875 (Box 1B, Folder 15)
    - Two American Indian Women Posed Sitting, circa 1875 (Box 1B, Folder 16)
    - American Indian Boy Posed Sitting, Half Figure, 1864-1866 (Box 1C, Folder 17)
      Sixth-plate hand-tinted tintype in a full leather case.
      One-cent revenue stamp on the verso of the plate.
    - American Indian Boy Posed Sitting and Holding a Club, Bust Figure, circa 1860 (Box 1C, Folder 18)
      Sixth-plate hand-tinted tintype in a full thermoplastic case manufactured by Littlefield, Parsons, and Company.
  - Orotone
    - Pillsbury, Arthur Clarence
      - American Indian Infant in a Cradleboard, circa 1910 (Box 1C, Folder 19)
- Card Photographs, 1863-circa 1910; Series II; 1.67; (3 boxes)
  Biographical/Historical note
  Created chiefly during the nineteenth century, card photographs encompass commercially-produced photographs mounted on thick cardboard that have dimensions slightly larger than the photographic prints. The photographer's name or insignia is usually printed or embossed on the cardboard mount. The versos of the cards often bear the imprint of the photographer.
  Images by a single photographer may appear in multiple subseries.
  Series II is organized into seven subseries: Cartes-de-visite, Cabinet Photographs, Imperial Photographs, Promenade Photographs, Boudoir Photographs, Victoria Cards, and Other Card Photographs.
  - Cartes-de-visite
    Introduced in 1854, the carte-de-visite, or carte, was generally a 5.7 x 8.9 centimeters (2.25 x 3.5 inches) photograph, usually a full or bust-length portrait of an individual, mounted on a 6.4 x 10.2 centimeters (2.5 x 4 inches) paper card.
    Arranged alphabetically by photographer or studio followed by material made by unidentified creators.
    - Adams, C. A.
      - American Indian Child, Woman, and Man, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Anson, Rufus P.
      - Bright Bird (Aratêve, Irétabe, Irataba, Yar-Tav, or Eecheyara Tav), a Mohave Indian Man, circa 1864-1865 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Brady, Mathew B.
      - Southern Plains Delegation of American Indians in the White House Conservatory, Washington, D.C., 1863 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 22)
        The American Indians in the front row, left to right: War Bonnet, Standing in the Water, and Lean Bear, all Cheyenne Indians, as well as Yellow Wolf, a Kiowa Indian. The American Indians in the second row are unidentified.
        Interpreter William Simpson Smith and the agent Samuel G. Colley stand at the left of the group.
        The European American woman standing at the far right is identified as Mary Todd Lincoln.
    - Carter, Charles William
      - Shoshoni Indian Man and Boy, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Caswell, William, and William H. Davy
      - Four American Indian Men, circa 1870-1875 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Chamberlain, William Gunnison
      - Mounted Cartes-de-visite, circa 1871 (Box 20, Folder 25)
        Fifteen cartes-de-visite including portraits of Ute Indians, Crow Indians, Dakota Indians, Cheyenne Indians, Arapahoe Indians, Comanche Indians and Navajo Indians, compiled and mounted on a board by William Gunnison Chamberlain.
        Individuals include: Navajo Indian woman, Juanita, wife of Manuelito, by William Henry Jackson, circa 1885; Ute Indian man, Tab-u-cha-kat, by William Gunnison Chamberlain, circa 1862-77; Crow Indian woman; White River Ute Indian man, Chief Uncachef; an Unca Indian chief, No. 4210, by William Henry Jackson; Ute Indian Chief, Johnson; Spotted Tail, Sioux chief by William Gunnison Chamberlain, circa 1875; Group photo of Cheyenne Indian and Arapaho Indian chiefs; Ma-Ha; Yorn-Ko, Ouray's runner; Washington, a Ute Indian chief; and other Braves and Warriors.
    - Cross, William Richard
      - Yankton Indian Man, 1878-1890 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - E. & H.T. Anthony
      - American Indian Man, circa 1868 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        Inscribed on the verso: "From the collection of Thos. Nast."
    - Fearon, R. N.
      - Dakota Indian Boy at the Opening into a Tipi, circa 1867 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Gurnsey, Byron H.
      - Little Raven or Young Crow (Hosa), an Arapaho Indian Man, circa 1869 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Hamilton, James H.
      - American Indian Woman and Girl, 1864-1867 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Hansen, Anders
      - Album of Cartes-de-visite, circa 1880-1887 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        Album with four cartes-de-visite photographs of American Indians, probably Ho-Chunk Indians.
        Individuals include: Vi-Pa-Ma-Ga-Na-Ijei-Ka, an American Indian Man; Djai and Tordenschef, an American Indian woman and an American Indian man; Tjaskagonga and Vihonga, two American Indian women; and Big Feiver or Star Tea, an American Indian man.
    - Hoard, E. Harry, and Charles A. Tenney
      - Quay-We-Zance or Kway-We-Zance, Ojibwa Indian Man, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Wais-cow-be-tung and Ke-na-be-quence, Ojibwa Indian Men, at White Earth, Minnesota, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - White Earth, Minnesota, Including Office and Warehouse, circa 1872 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - White Earth, Minnesota, Burial Ground, circa 1872 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Houseworth, Thomas
      - Yo-Semite Falls (No. 1111), 1867 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Jackson, William Henry
      - Good Bear (Cu-Roox-Ta-Ri-Ha), Pawnee Indian Man, 1867 June (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Driving A Herd (Ta-Caw-Deex-Taw-See-Ux), Pawnee Indian Man, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Jackson, William Henry, and Edward Jackson
      - Four Sac and Fox Indians and an Interpreter, circa 1867 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Lawrence & Houseworth
      - An Indian Rancheria in the Sierra Nevada Mountains (No. 601), circa 1866 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Washoe Indians -- The Chief's Family (No. 604), circa 1866 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Lewis, Richard A.
      - Low Dog, Oglala Indian Man, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Lucas, James H.
      - Standing Rock Indian Reservation, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - McKenney, Albert S.
      - Two American Indian Men, circa 1868; (2 cartes-de-visite) (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Morgan, William H.
      - Three American Indian Men, Identified as Divinity Students at Carlisle Indian Industrial School, Pennsylvania, and a European American Man, circa 1880 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Morrow, Stanley Julius
      - Red Cloud or Scarlet Cloud (Makhpiya-luta, Mahpina Luta), Oglala Indian Man (No. 3), 1876 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Standing Bear (Ma-chú-nu-zhe, Ma-chú-na-zhe or Mantcunanjin), a Ponca Indian Chief (No. 1), circa 1876 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Big Snake (We-Ca-Ton-Ga or Wase-A-Tonga), a Ponca Indian Man (No. 2), circa 1876 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Medicine Bear, Medicine Bear Track, or Mysterious Grizzly Bear (Mato Wakan or Ma-To-Ican or Ma-To-O-A-Wa-Kan or Ma-To-Wuh-Kan), Yankton Indian Man (No. 4), circa 1876 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - White Bull or Joseph White Bull (Thatháŋka Ská), Miniconjou Indian Man (No. 5), circa 1876 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Energy Searcher and Lean Man, Hidatsa Indian Men (No. 6), circa 1876 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Crow's Breast or Crow's Belly (First Chief) and Lean Wolf or Poor Wolf (Second Chief), Hidatsa Indian Men (No. 7), circa 1876 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - Spotted Tail or Jumping Buffalo (Siŋté Glešká, Sinte-Galeshka, or Tshin-Tah-Ge-Las-Kah), Brulé Indian Man, with his Wife and their Daughter (No. 8), circa 1876 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - American Indian Infant in a Cradleboard (No. 9), circa 1876 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - People on Street in Deadwood, Dakota Territory (No. 10), circa 1876 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - Buckskin Lodge, Dakota Indian Prisoners, Battle Flag of George Armstrong Custer Captured at the Battle of Slim Buttes, and the Officers in Command of the Charge (No. 11), circa 1876 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - Two Yankton Indian Men (No. 12), circa 1876 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Mueller, John
      - American Indian Man, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - American Indian Girl, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Powelson, Abraham, Jr.
      - American Indian Woman, circa 1868 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Savage, Charles Roscoe
      - Paiute Indian Man, circa 1865 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - American Indian Man and Woman, circa 1865 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Tyson, Isaac G
      - Joseph Ambler (He-Him-Cha) and Lizzie Cleaver, Iowa Indian School Children at the Great Nemaha Agency, Kansas, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      - British (Nag-Ga-Rash, Naggarash, Na-Ga-Wash, Nagarash, or Nag-a-Rash), an Iowa Indian Man, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      - Brier, Briar, or Bear (To-Hee), an Iowa Indian Man, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      - Kihega or Ki-ke-ga, an Iowa Indian Man, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      - Sac and Fox Indian Girl, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 67)
      - John Mah-hee, an Iowa Indian Man, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - Iowa Indian Boy and Girl, School Children at the Great Nemaha Agency, Kansas, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      - Henry Jones (Su-ton-tha-nah), an Iowa Indian Boy, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Upton, Benjamin Franklin
      - Five Dakota Indian Men and a Dakota Indian Woman at Fort Snelling, Minnesota, circa 1864 (Box 2, Folder 71)
        Misidentified on verso as Winneshiek and Warriors in Council
    - Whitney, Joel Emmons
      - Cut Nose or One Who Stands on a Cloud (Marpiya Oki Najin, Mahpe-o-ke-na-ji, or Poge Baksa), Dakota Indian Man, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      - Copy Photograph of People Escaping from the Indian Massacre at Dinner on a Prairie, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 73)
        Original photograph attributed to Adrian John Ebell.
      - Noon Day (Now-We-Ke-Shick or Now-We-Ge-Shick), Ojibwa Indian Man, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      - Mountain Chief (O-Ge-Mah-O-Cha-Wub), Ojibwa Indian Man from Leech Lake, Minnesota, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 75)
      - Hole in the Day or Joseph Kwiwisens (Bug-O-Nay-Gee-Shig, Bugonaygeeshig, Bug-O-Na-Ghe-Zhisk, or Po-Go-Nay-Ge-Shick), Ojibwa Indian Man, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - Little Crow, Dakota Indian Man, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - Buffalo (Bizhiki, Be-She-Kee, Beshekee, or Pezeke), Ojibwa Indian Man from Leech Lake, Minnesota, circa 1862 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - Dakota Indian Man and Children Posed Sitting in Front of a Tipi and Drying Meat, circa 1862 (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - Ah-Pe-Ma-Za, Dakota Indian Man, circa 1862 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      - Beautiful Night or Good Night Woman (Han-Ye-Tu Was-Te or Hanyetu-Washte-Win), Mdewakanton Indian Woman, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 81)
      - Old Man (Aw-Ke-Wen-Zee or Awkewenzee), Ojibwa Indian Man of the Lac Courte Oreilles Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians of Wisconsin, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      - Medicine Bottle (Wa-Kan-O-Zhan-Zahn or Wa-Kan-O-Zan-Zan), Dakota Indian Man, Engaged in the Massacre of 1862, Prisoner at Fort Snelling, Minnesota, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - Big Dog (Ne-Bah-Qua-On), Ojibwa Indian Man of the Pillager Band of Chippewa Indians, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Unidentified Photographers
      - Group of Photographs Formerly Owned by Charles R. Hunt
        Custodial History
        The verso of each carte-de-visite includes the autograph of "Chas. R. Hunt."
        - Four American Indian Men, One Man has a Cleft Palate, circa 1865-1870 (Box 2, Folder 85)
        - Two American Indian Men, circa 1865-1870 (Box 2, Folder 86)
        - American Indian Man with a Cleft Palate, circa 1865-1870 (Box 2, Folder 87)
        - American Indian Man Holding a Club, circa 1865-1870 (Box 2, Folder 88)
      - Good Bear, Dakota Indian Man, circa 1865 (Box 2, Folder 89)
      - Rolling Water (Minneloosa), Arapaho Indian Man, circa 1868 (Box 2, Folder 90)
      - American Indian Man, circa 1865 (Box 2, Folder 91)
      - American Indian Man, circa 1865 (Box 2, Folder 92)
      - American Indian Man, circa 1865 (Box 2, Folder 93)
      - American Indian Man, circa 1865 (Box 2, Folder 94)
      - Three American Indian Men, circa 1865 (Box 2, Folder 95)
      - Tipi Frames, circa 1865 (Box 2, Folder 96)
      - Meat Drying on a Wooden Frame in Front of a Tipi, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 97)
      - Four Ojibwa Indian Men and an Ojibwa Indian Boy (No. 743), circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 98)
      - Studio Portrait of Nine American Indians, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 99)
        Photographer's blindstamps in the image of "EA" and "JG."
      - John Jumper (Hemha Micco), Seminole Indian Man, circa 1875 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Cabinet Photographs
    Introduced in 1862, cabinet photographs were photographic prints with dimensions around 11.4 x 16.5 centimeters (4.5 by 6.5 inches) mounted on cardboard and generally used for portraits.
    Related Archival Materials note
    Associated Materials: Additional cabinet photographs can also be found in Series V. Photograph Albums and Volumes.
    - Barry, David Francis
      - Standing Rock, Dakota Territory, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 101)
      - Copy photograph of George Armstrong Custer, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 102)
      - Crow Eagle, Fool Thunder, Slow White Buffalo and Iron Thunder, Dakota Indians, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 103)
      - Yellow Hawk, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 104)
      - Red Cloud (Mahpíya Lúta), Dakota Indian, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 105)
      - Gall (Phizí) and his Nephew, William Hawk, Teton Indian Men, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Barthelmess, Christian
      - Self-portrait of Christian Barthelmess Wearing a United States Army Band Uniform, circa 1888 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Black, James Wallace
      - Frank Hamilton Cushing (Tenatsali), a European American Man Dressed as a Zuni Bow Priest, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 108)
      - Zuni Indian Delegation with Frank Hamilton Cushing, a European American Man, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 109)
        Left to right, Governor Laiyuaitsailus (Hai-ya-ah-tsai-hi or Pedro Pino); Naiyutchi (Nai-uchi); Cushing; Governor Pah-lo-wah-ti-wa (Patricio Pino); Kiasiwa (Ki-a-si); and Nanahe (Na-na-he), a Hopi adopted by the Zuni.
    - Buehman, Henry
      - Apache Man, Old Man, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Choate, John Nicholas
      - Sarah Mather, a European American Woman, and Three Menominee Indian Girls (No. 84), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Davis, Lee
      - Kiowa Indian Infant in a Papoose, identified as White Field Lone Wolf, Grandson of Chief Lone Wolf the Younger, circa 1910 (Box 3, Folder 112)
      - Chief Lone Wolf the Younger and his wife, Akeiquodle, Kiowa Indians, circa 1910 (Box 3, Folder 113)
      - Skyny Baw Paw, Kiowa Indian man, circa 1910 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Drum, Oscar
      - Osage Indian Camp, Oklahoma, circa 1906 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Eisenmann, Charles
      - American Indian Juggler, circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Gardner, Alexander